## Adrian Alejandro Vacca Bonilla

System and Computing Engineer, 9-year experience, focusing on Business Intelligence projects. Strong skills in relational databases and data modelling. Expert in QlikView, Qlik Sense and Power BI development. Knowledge in technologies like Java, Oracle, Pentaho and SAP.

### avaccab@gmail.com

Av Universitaria #65 02 Apto 4204 Tunja

Colombia +57 313-402-87-37

### **CAREER HISTORY**

## STRATESYS SAS, Technical Consultant

DFC 2021 - PRESENT

Developing Power BI datasets and reports in Telefonica project.

## **TEAM INTERNATIONAL SAS, Data Engineer**

AUG 2018 - DEC 2021

Developed Power BI Reports in HairClub project.

Designed and developed Qlik Sense applications for Inventory and Finance in Imerys customer.

### MANAR TECHNOLOGIES SAS, Qlik Consultant

DEC 2015 - JUL 2018

Designed and Developed business intelligence applications in both QlikView and Qlik Sense.

Sized projects and built architecture documents

Trained final users in Qlik products.

Led Plastilene and JTI projects.

Supported presales activities building Qlik Sense Demos.

## **DIANA CORPORACION SAS**, Business Intelligence Analyst

DEC 2013 - NOV 2015

Analyzed, designed and built QlikView applications

Extracted data from SAP, SQL Server and Postgre

Supported and maintain BI solutions

Managed Oracle databases

### **SKILLS**

Power BI Power Apps QlikView Qlik Sense Set Analysis DAX SAP Pentaho

## CERTIFICATIONS

Olik Sense Business Analyst (June 2017 Release) QSBA20170240

Qlik Sense Data Architect (June 2017 Release) QSDA20170024

QlikView 11 Designer QV3552DES

QlikView 11 Developer QV3294DEV

DA-100 Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Microsoft Power Bl

Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC) ScrumStudy

# **DEPARTAMENTO ADMINISTRATIVO NACIONAL DE ESTADÍSTICA**, Development Engineer

APR 2012 - NOV 2013

Analyzed, designed, and developed of ETL processes

Executed and supervised data loads

### **LANGUAGES**

English (B2) Spanish (Native)

#### **EDUCATION**

**Universidad Pedagógica y Tecnologica de Colombia,** Tunja— Bachelor's degree in Computing and Systems Engineering

FEB. 2006 - DEC 2011

**Universidad Pedagógica y Tecnologica de Colombia,** Tunja — Postgraduate Diploma in Databases

JUL 2011 – JUL 2012

### **PROJECTS**

## HairClub (Hair Restoration Industry)

MAR 2020-DEC 2021

Designed Power BI architecture.

Created datasets, reports and dashboards for marketing in Power BI.

### Imerys. (Mining Industry)

AUG 2019-MAR 2021

Migrated Inventory and logistics reports from SSRS to Qlik Sense

## Japan Tobacco International (Tobacco Industry). One Data Project

OCT 2017-MAY 2018

Migrated Qlik Sense Asia Data Models to Americas Regional.

Created new dashboards for Analysis of Nielsen Data (Volume and Share of Market) for the six countries of Americas Region.

## Plastilene SA (Polymer Industry). Financial Project

MAY 2016-DEC 2016

Designed architecture of entire deployment using Qlik Deployment Framework.

Developed using Qlik Sense Financial Dashboards, including P&L, Free Cash Flow, Expenses Analysis and Profitability, from SAP extractions to final User Interface.

## Organización Terpel (Oil and Gas Industry)

DEC 2015- APR 2016

Designed Extraction and Transformation from SAP Project System module.

Created of Project Management dashboards (QlikView) joining SAP Financial and Project modules.